Inventory of the Stone-Moore Papers 1860-1957
Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
Special Collections, Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
Stone-Moore Papers 1860-1957 1880-1950
Special Collections Research Center
01/Mss. Acc. 2010.085
1.49
Personal papers, correspondence and business records of Edward L. Stone (1869-1938) and his son-in-law, Franklin Moore of Roanoke, Virginia. Both men owned the Roanoke Printing and Manufacturing Company and were involved in various civic organizations.
Stone, Edward L. (Edward Lee), 1864-1938; Moore, L. Franklin arrangement
Administrative Information
Conditions Governing Access
Collection is open to all researchers.
Acquisition Information
The materials were acquired by Special Collections Research Center from Tim Abbott. on 02/02/2010.
Biographical Note
Edward Lee Stone was born September 15, 1864, in Liberty, Virginia (now known as Bedford, VA) and died in 1938. After working for John P. Bell's printing company, Stone was promoted and eventually took over the business. He became a wealthy and prominent citizen of Roanoake through his business, the Stone Printing and Manufacturing Company. He also played an important role in his local community through various civic organizations and clubs. His wife was Minnie Fishburn and his daughter Mary Katherine Stone. For further information, see http://scrc.swem.wm.edu/wiki/index.php/Edward_L._Stone Further information about this individual or organization may be available in the Special Collections Research Center Wiki: http://scrc.swem.wm.edu/wiki/index.php/Edward L. Stone (Edward Lee).
Scope and Contents
Personal papers, correspondence and business records of Edward L. Stone (1869-1938) and his son-in-law, Franklin Moore of Roanoke, Virginia. Both men owned the Roanoke Printing and Manufacturing Company and were involved in various civic organizations.
Arrangement of Materials
This collection is organized into five series: Series 1: Correspondence and Personal Papers, Series 2: Photographs, Series 3: Business and Financial Documents, Series 4: Political Tracts and Series 5: Ephemera.
Additional Information
Index Terms
This Collection is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Corporate Name:
Stone Printing and Manufacturing Company (Roanoke, Va.)
Genre/Form of Material:
Business records; Correspondence; Photographs
Geographic Name:
Roanoke (Va.)--History.
Topical Term:
Printing--Virginia--History.
Detailed Description of the Collection
- Correspondence and Personal Papers, 1880-1952; id67046
  - id67051 (Box 1)
    - Stone Correspondence, 1880-1899; id67053 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Stone Correspondence, 1920-1935; id67052 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Stone-Hunter Correspondence, 1931; id67054 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Stone-Hoffer Correspondence, 1932-1934; id67055 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Stone Correspondence, Undated; id67056 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Stone Greeting Cards, Invitations and Unsigned Notes, Undated; id67057 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Moore Correspondence, 1938-1939; id67058 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Moore Correspondence, 1940-1945; id67059 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Moore Correspondence, 1946-1953; id67060 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Moore-Everett Waddey Correspondence, 1939; id67061 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Moore-Noland Correspondence, 1944-1952; id67062 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - id67063 (Box 2)
    - Moore Correspondence, undated; id67064 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Moore Greeting Cards, Invitations and Unsigned Notes, undated; id67065 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Moore Greeting Cards, Invitations and Unsigned Notes, undated; id67066 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Grandfather Moore Correspondence, 1951; id67067 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Photographs, circa 1940s; id67047
  - id67068 (Box 2)
    - Fishing Trip Photographs, circa 1940s; id67069 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Moore Family Photographs, circa 1940s; id67070 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Business and Financial Documents, 1860-1957; id67048
  - id67071 (Box 2)
    - Stone Financial Records, 1860-1924; id67072 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Roanoke Community Fund, 1925-1939; id67073 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Roanoke Community Fund, 1939-1950; id67074 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - id67045 (Box 3)
    - Roanoke Hospital, 1931-1939; id67075 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Virginia Manufacturers Association, 1936-1945; id67076 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Virginia Manufacturers Association, 1940; id67077 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Financial Records for Virginia Railroads, 1939-1952; id67078 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - YMCA Roanoke, 1945; id67079 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Rotary Club of Roanoke, 1945-1949; id67080 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Charity Solicitations, 1945-1952; id67081 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Shenandoah Club, 1946; id67082 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Princess Anne Club, 1948-1949; id67083 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Virginia Military Institute, 1950-1951; id67085 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Stockholders Reports, 1935-1948; id67086 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - id67084 (Box 4)
    - Stockholders Reports, 1949-1957; id67087 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Political Tracts, 1935-1950; id67049
  - id67088 (Box 4)
    - Political Tracts and Correspondence Regarding Inflation, 1935-1936; id67089 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Political and Economic Tracts, 1940-1950; id67090 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Ephemera, 1882-1956; id67050
  - id67091 (Box 4)
    - Printed Materials, 1882-1949; id67092 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Printed Materials, 1950-1956; id67094 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Mass Mail Ephemera, 1940s-1950s; id67095 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - id67093 (Box 5)
    - Printing Trade Ephemera, circa 1930s-1940s; id67096 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Stone Company Prints, undated; id67097 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Newspapers, 1933-1950; id67098 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - YWCA Roanoke Pamphlets, 1949; id67100 (Box 5, Folder 4)